<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Shamim&#39;s Summaries</title>
        <link>https://shamimaktar.github.io/</link>
        <description>This is My New Hugo Site</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 16:13:24 &#43;0600</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://shamimaktar.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>100 years of the A-Matrix</title>
    <link>https://shamimaktar.github.io/100_years_of_the_a_matrix/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 16:13:24 &#43;0600</pubDate>
    <author>Md. Shamim Aktar</author>
    <guid>https://shamimaktar.github.io/100_years_of_the_a_matrix/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/wright.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>In the year 1922, Sewall Wright first documented the idea of tracing paths to establish the relationships among animals. Though he was not working in the field of agriculture, his discovery laid the path (pun intended) toward revolutionizing the breeding and agriculture sector. Followed by Wright, scientists like Thompson, Henderson, Quaas, Meuwissen, Luo, Van Vleck, Mistzal, and many others extended his idea and derived the A-matrix or additive genetic relationship matrix or Numerator Relationship Matrix (NRM), Inverse of A-matrix (more realistic), and finally the Genomic Relationship Matrix (exploiting the Mendelian sampling term).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How to install VCE 6.0.2 on a Windows x86 64-bit machine</title>
    <link>https://shamimaktar.github.io/vc6/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 16:13:24 &#43;0600</pubDate>
    <author>Md. Shamim Aktar</author>
    <guid>https://shamimaktar.github.io/vc6/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/fli.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>**This is the version6 of VCE a package for estimating (co)variance components by REML and Gibbs Sampling The vce6 directory contains 3 subdirectories: bin - contains executables for a number of computing platforms doc - contains the documentation in A4 and US Letter format examples - contains just that: data and parameter files that should run out of the box after installation**   1. First, go to this link and download the 53.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>A brief overview of the popular research streams in Animal Husbandry</title>
    <link>https://shamimaktar.github.io/first_post/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 13:09:37 &#43;0600</pubDate>
    <author>Md. Shamim Aktar</author>
    <guid>https://shamimaktar.github.io/first_post/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/featured-image.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Find out about the popular research areas in the animal sciences and the purpose of this blog</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
