<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>ABG - Category - Shamim&#39;s Summaries</title>
        <link>https://shamimaktar.github.io/categories/abg/</link>
        <description>ABG - Category - Shamim&#39;s Summaries</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 16:13:24 &#43;0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shamimaktar.github.io/categories/abg/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Variance component estimation with AIREMLF90 for Single Trait Analysis</title>
    <link>https://shamimaktar.github.io/airemlf90_vce/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 16:13:24 &#43;0600</pubDate>
    <author>Md. Shamim Aktar</author>
    <guid>https://shamimaktar.github.io/airemlf90_vce/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/airemlf90.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>In the previous post, I tried to show how to solve MME to derive BLUP values with assumed variance components. We need to estimate actual variance components of the animals under study in practical application. Especially, if:
 we are interested in a new trait, from which no parameters are available variances and covariances might have changed over time considerable changes have occurred in a population e.g. due to recent importations.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Single Trait Analysis with known/assumed variance components using BLUPF90&#43;</title>
    <link>https://shamimaktar.github.io/blupf90_single_trait_mme_solver/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 16:13:24 &#43;0600</pubDate>
    <author>Md. Shamim Aktar</author>
    <guid>https://shamimaktar.github.io/blupf90_single_trait_mme_solver/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/blupf90.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Estimation of breeding values is at the core of Animal Breeding for genetic improvement of livestock. The BLUP methodology solving MME bt Henderson is standard in this regard. BLUPF90+ is a combination of programs with which we can solve MME for simultaneously getting BLUE and BLUP values of animals for trait/s.
 BLUPF90&#43;   In this example, we will try to solve the single trait (Pre weaning weight gain, WWG) with fixed effect (sex) and random effect (animal) from Chapter 3 data on animal model of Mrode(2014).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>100 years of the A-Matrix</title>
    <link>https://shamimaktar.github.io/100_years_of_the_a_matrix/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 16:13:24 &#43;0600</pubDate>
    <author>Md. Shamim Aktar</author>
    <guid>https://shamimaktar.github.io/100_years_of_the_a_matrix/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/wright.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>In the year 1922, Sewall Wright first documented the idea of tracing paths to establish the relationships among animals. Though he was not working in the field of agriculture, his discovery laid the path (pun intended) toward revolutionizing the breeding and agriculture sector. Followed by Wright, scientists like Thompson, Henderson, Quaas, Meuwissen, Luo, Van Vleck, Mistzal, and many others extended his idea and derived the A-matrix or additive genetic relationship matrix or Numerator Relationship Matrix (NRM), Inverse of A-matrix (more realistic), and finally the Genomic Relationship Matrix (exploiting the Mendelian sampling term).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How to install VCE 6.0.2 on a Windows x86 64-bit machine</title>
    <link>https://shamimaktar.github.io/vc6/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 16:13:24 &#43;0600</pubDate>
    <author>Md. Shamim Aktar</author>
    <guid>https://shamimaktar.github.io/vc6/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/fli.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>**This is the version6 of VCE a package for estimating (co)variance components by REML and Gibbs Sampling The vce6 directory contains 3 subdirectories: bin - contains executables for a number of computing platforms doc - contains the documentation in A4 and US Letter format examples - contains just that: data and parameter files that should run out of the box after installation**   1. First, go to this link and download the 53.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
